<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="descriptions">
    <item>
        "More air in means more oxygen in the blood and therefore in the brain. Breath through your nose and you'll notice that you use your diaphragm more,drawing air deeper into your lungs.
        Several deep breaths can also help to relax you,which is conducive to clearer thinking." </item>
    <item>
        "A simple meditation you can do right now is just closing your eyes and paying attention to your breath.
        Tensing up your muscles and then relaxing them to start may help. When your mind wanders, just bring your attention back to your breath. Five or ten minutes of this will usually relax you, clear your mind, and leave you more ready for any mental task." </item>
    <item>
        "Sit up straight.
        Posture affects your thinking process.
        Prove it to yourself by doing math in your head while slouching, looking at the floor and letting your mouth hang open.
        Then do the mental math while sitting up straight, keeping your mouth closed and looking forward or slightly upwards.
        You'll notice that it's easier to think with the latter posture." </item>
    <item>
        "This supplement has been shown in clinical studies to increase lucidity and rate of learning.
        It activates cell-to-cell communication, helps regulate cell growth, improves the functioning of the special receptors found on cells, and prepares cells for activity.
        In other words, it can help your brain power.
        It's also thought to reverse memory decline.
        Phosphatidylserine has no known adverse side effects." </item>


<item>
    "Intuition can be an important part of brainpower.
    Einstein and others have relied heavily on their intuitive hunches.
    Quiet your mind and listen. Take time each day to experience silence.
    Practice calming your mind by using whatever breathing or meditative technique you prefer.
    Let go of the inclination to think, or analyze, and try to know everything. Be open and listen.
    Let your thoughts roam and be open to the ideas and solutions that come to you.
    When you listen to your intuition it connects you with a greater knowledge.
    It usually communicates through symbols, feelings and emotions.
    Learn to trust your hunches and gut feelings.
    If something doesn't feel right  chances are it isn't.
    What may be right for one person could be totally wrong for you.
    How many times have you had that feeling in your stomach compelling you to do, or not do, something for no apparent reason?
    Listening to it probably helped you avoid a traffic accident, or led you to be at the right place and time for getting that great job, or meeting that special person.
    Your intuition is your inner guide, so learn to trust it.
    At first, trusting it may be a bit scary, but allow it the opportunity to develop." </item>

    <item>
    "Before you go to bed at night, reflect upon questions and issues for which you couldn't find solutions during the day.
    Think about and explore different possibilities.
    This will trigger your imagination and put your subconscious to work at furnishing you with creative solutions while you sleep.
    Be sure to have a pen and paper handy so when you wake up during the night with some great ideas, you can write them down." </item>
   <item>
            "This extract, derived from an alkaloid found in the Periwinkle plant, is used as a cerebral vasodilator.
            It increases blood flow to the brain, which improves its oxygenation and thereby increases mental alertness and acuity.
            Research suggests it may also be the most powerful memory enhancer available to date." </item>

        <item>
            "This common herb may have an effect on the brain when the scent is inhaled.
            We are waiting for the research, but some people swear that just sniffing rosemary wakes up their brain.
            It seems safe, so if you have rosemary in your spice rack, give it a try."

        </item>

        <item>
            "The leaves of this tree have been proven to increase blood flow to the brain.
            The trees are often planted in parks.
            My friends and I used to eat a few leaves when we wanted a brain boost.
            It is also inexpensive, if you buy the capsules or tea at any health food store."
        </item>


        <item>
            "Other foods that may be good for your brain include:
            Avocados, bananas, lean beef, brewer's yeast.
            broccoli, brown rice, brussel sprouts, cantaloupe, cheese,
            chicken, collard greens, eggs, flaxseed oil, legumes, oatmeal,
            oranges, peanut butter, peas, potatoes, romaine lettuce, salmon,
            soybeans, spinach, tuna, turkey, wheat germ, and yogurt."

        </item>

<item>
    "This is a compound extracted from the Chinese club moss.
    Researchers both in Israel and the U.S. have used it to treat alzheimer's.
    It improves memory and learning an seems to be very safe."
</item>

<item>
   " In a study at the University of California, researchers found that children who studied piano and sang daily in chorus, were much better at solving puzzles, and when tested, scored 80% higher in spatial intelligence than the non-musical group.
    In another study, 36 students were given three spatial reasoning tests on a standard IQ test.
    Just before the first test, they listened to Mozart's sonata for Two Pianos in D Major, K. 448 for ten minutes.
    Before the second test, they listened to a relaxation tape.
    Before the third, they sat in silence.
    The average scores for all 36 students: 1st test: 119. 2nd test: 111. 3rd test: 110.
    A nine-point boost from Mozart!"
</item>


        <item>
           " Alpha-lipoic acid (10 to 50 milligrams daily) improves memory and protects nerve cells."
        </item>
<item>
    "This is a great way to keep your brain in shape.
    Just get in the habit of asking questions often, even if it is only in your own mind.
    Why are taller buildings better?
    What is the purpose of curbs?
    Ask anything that comes to mind, and ponder the possible answers."

</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>